{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following hepatitis viruses is not RNA virus?", "opta": "Hepatitis A virus", "optb": "Hepatitis B virus", "optc": "Hepatitis E virus", "optd": "Hepatitis G virus", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following nucleic acid is present in hepatitis B virus?", "opta": "dsDNA", "optb": "ssRNA", "optc": "ssDNA", "optd": "dsRNA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The agent representing an isolate of hepatitis G virus is", "opta": "GBA-A", "optb": "GBV-B", "optc": "GBV-C", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hepatitis G virus belongs to the family", "opta": "Caliciviridae", "optb": "Flaviviridae", "optc": "Hepadnaviridae", "optd": "Coronaviridae", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transmission of hepatitis G virus is", "opta": "Parenterally", "optb": "Sexually", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most serious infection is", "opta": "superinfection of an HBsAg carrier by HDV", "optb": "infection with HBV alone", "optc": "coinfection of HBVand HDV", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following specimens contain/s hepatitis B virus in an infected person?", "opta": "Blood", "optb": "Semen", "optc": "Saliva", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vertical transmission may be seen in", "opta": "Hepatitis B virus", "optb": "Hepatitis C virus", "optc": "Hepatitis D virus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following viral infections can result in chronic carrier state?", "opta": "HBV", "optb": "HCV", "optc": "HDV", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most reliable test for detection of hepatitis E infection is", "opta": "ELISA test for IgM anti-HEV", "optb": "Western blot assay for IgM anti-HEV", "optc": "Polymerase chain reaction for detection of HEV RNA", "optd": "ELISA test for IgG anti-HEV", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hepatocellular carcinoma (Hepatoma) may be caused by", "opta": "Hepatitis A virus", "optb": "Hepatitis C virus", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The defective satellite virus is", "opta": "hepatitis B", "optb": "hepatitis C", "optc": "hepatitis D", "optd": "hepatitis A", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All of the following viruses are enveloped except", "opta": "Hepatitis A virus", "optb": "Hepatitis B virus", "optc": "Hepatitis C virus", "optd": "Hepatitis D virus", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The diagnosis of hepatitis A virus infection is carried out from the method based on", "opta": "aminotransferase levels", "optb": "detection of faecal HAV by immunoelectron microscopy", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "detection of IgM anti-HAV by ELISA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not correct for hepatitis A virus?", "opta": "It can be grown in cell cultures of primate and human cells", "optb": "It is one of the most stable viruses infecting humans", "optc": "It may cause hepatocellular carcinoma", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following viruses can be transmitted by the parenteral route?", "opta": "HBV", "optb": "HCV", "optc": "HDV", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The viruses, which is/are transmitted by parenteral and sexual routes is/are", "opta": "Hepatitis B virus", "optb": "Hepatitis C virus", "optc": "Hepatitis G virus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following antigenic types of hepatitis B virus is present in the envelope?", "opta": "HbsAg", "optb": "HBcAg", "optc": "HBeAg", "optd": "HBxAg", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The development of hepatocellular carcinoma is associated with", "opta": "ground squirrel hepatitis virus", "optb": "hepatitis B virus", "optc": "woodchuck hepatitis virus", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following antigenic types of hepatitis B virus is prevalent in India?", "opta": "Adw", "optb": "Adr", "optc": "Ayw", "optd": "Ayr", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}